# Yuedi (Eddy) Liang

Cell: (626) 429-5321 || Email: <u>yuedilia@usc.edu</u> | Los Angeles, CA LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/yuedi-liang</u> || GitHub: <u>github.com/Emericen</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Developer with 2+ years of project experience in both frontend and backend development, along with algorithm, data structure, and object-oriented design. Strong programming skills in Java, Python, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Seeking entry-level Software Engineering positions starting August 2022.

### **EDUCATION**

# **University of Southern California**

Los Angeles, CA Aug 2021 – Aug 2022

Master of Science, System Architecting and Engineering

Aug 2021 – Aug 2022

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2016 – May 2020

#### **SKILLS**

• Programming Languages: Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- Frameworks/Tools: Rest API, React, Vue, Flask, Django, Spring, Tomcat, Hibernate, Flutter
- Cloud/Database: AWS, GCP, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Flashcard Urumqi, China

Full Stack Engineer / Co-Founder

Oct 2020 – Jul 2021

- Co-Founded an online platform to facilitate one-on-one English tutoring during COVID-19 social distancing
- Presented prototype to stakeholders with **Adobe XD** upon gathering user story
- Created cloud MongoDB database hosted by Tencent Cloud, and offered backend services through Rest API
- Implemented mobile app using Flutter, designed website with React
- Provided stable video communications in Xinjiang, automated students' appointment making, and English vocabulary memorization based on the forgetting curve
- Achieved peak daily active user of 40+ students from elementary and middle school

GF Securities

Guangzhou, China

Frontend Software Engineer Intern

Aug 2020 – Dec 2020

- Maintained the company portfolio management software frontend built in React and deployed on Alibaba Cloud
- Upgraded input form by introducing component library **AntD** to replace barebone HTML and CSS
- Built date selection window to replace multiple text input for year/month/day to simplify user interaction and verification
- Implemented form autofill with Excel feature allowing staff to upload financial statement files instead of typing data by hand, which reduced manual work by 75%

#### **PROJECTS**

Postmates Clone: A Food Ordering Application. Git: https://github.com/Emericen/online-order-backend.git

- Provided services including user authentication, menu searching, ordering, and checkout with **Rest API**
- Loosely decouple backend MVC components and allow authentication security using **Spring** framework
- Accessed and operated relational data storage with **Hibernate** ORM framework
- Build the client-side UI with React.IS

# Airbnb Clone: A Homestay Rental Application. Git: https://github.com/Emericen/staybooking-backend.git

- Established backend services including homestay CRUD operations and token-based authentication
- Stored user-generated data and media files using MySQL incorporated with Google Cloud Storage
- Provided geo-based homestay search with **Elastic Search** to support search based on user's selected locations
- Deployed the backend service to Google App Engine for better scalability and reliability

## TikTok News: A TikTok-like News App on Android. Git: https://github.com/Emericen/TinNews

- Developed in Android Studio with **Java**, and tested on emulators
- Integrated Retrofit to pull the latest news data from RESTFUL endpoint (newsapi.org)
- Utilized 3rd party CardStackView to support swipe gestures for liking/disliking the news
- Designed project based on Google Component Architectural MVVM Pattern